Finding Aid for John Judson Bagley papers, 1830, 1847-1900
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Judson Bagley papers 1830, 1847-1900
Bagley, John Judson, 1832-1881.
1 linear foot and 1 oversize folder
851 Aa 2 Ac
Detroit businessman, Republican governor of Michigan (1873-1876) and candidate for the US Senate in 1881; correspondence, speeches, newspaper clippings, and other materials concerning politics, business interests, and state government.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Mrs. John N. Bagley (Donor no. 1 ) and came to the library in October 1935. A few additional items were added in 2001 by John C. Phillips (donor no. 9128)
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
John Judson Bagley was born in Medina, Orleans County, NY, July 24, 1832. Around 1840, he moved with his parents to Constantine, Michigan. They subsequently moved to Owosso. In 1847 Bagley went to Detroit, where he was employed in a tobacco factory. He also engaged in other enterprises, such as banking, mining and manufacturing. He was also involved in politics, serving as chairman of the State Republican Committee from 1868 to 1870. In 1872 he was nominated and elected Governor of Michigan. He was re-elected in 1874 and served until 1877. He was an unsuccessful candidate for the United States Senate in 1881. He died later that year in San Francisco, Calif., Dec. 27, 1881.
The Bagley collection includes correspondence, speeches, newspaper clippings, and other materials concerning politics and his various business interests. There are also subject files relating to the Centennial Exposition at Philadelphia in 1876 which took place during his gubernatorial administration. The clipping files are of value for articles on Isaac P. Christiancy and Zachariah Chandler and for newspaper coverage of his term as governor and his unsuccessful campaign for senator.
Subjects:
Michigan--Politics and government--1866-1876.; Michigan--Politics and government--1877-1898.; Republican Party (Mich.).; Chandler, Zachariah, 1813-1879.; Christiancy, Isaac Peckham, 1812-1890.; Michigan State Capitol (Lansing, Mich.); Centennial Exhibition (1876: Philadelphia, Pa.).; Governors--Michigan.; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bagley, John Judson, 1832-1881.; Bagley family.; Detroit (Mich.); Detroit (Mich.)--Streets.; Funeral rites and ceremonies.; Michigan. State Centennial Board of Managers.; Streets--Michigan--Detroit.; Woodward Avenue (Detroit, Mich.); Governors--Michigan.
Contributors: Visual Materials
Bardwell, Jex.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Prints.; Stereographs.
- Correspondence
  - Undated (Box 1)
  - 1830, 1847-1863 (Box 1)
  - 1871-1875 (Box 1)
  - 1876 (Box 1)
  - 1877 (Box 1)
  - 1878 (Box 1)
  - January-December 1879, 10 folders (Box 1)
  - January-December 1880, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - January-March 1881 (Box 1)
  - 1887, 1900 (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Resolutions on his death, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning the Centennial Exposition at Philadelphia, 1876 (Box 1)
  - Speeches (Box 1)
  - Lists of Michigan Republicans (Box 1)
  - Proclamations (Box 1)
  - Poems (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1882-1891 of Mrs. Bagley (Box 1)
  - Miscellanea, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Certificates, cartoons, etc. (Folder Ac)
- Newspaper clippings
  - Bagley's term as Governor (Box 1)
  - Senatorial election in 1881, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Letters and speeches, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Obituary notices, 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Bagley Fountain (Box 1)
  - Memorial Fund (Box 1)
  - Isaac P. Christiancy (Box 1)
  - Zachariah Chandler (Box 1)
  - Unitarian Festival in Boston, 1880 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous subjects, 2 folders (Box 1)